Jennifer, are you ready?
Directors,
are you ready? Okay.
Good afternoon and welcome to the
January 30th, 2026 city council work
session. Today's topic will provide
information and updates about potential
renovation to the municipal building.
No votes will be taken and no questions
or comments will be received from the
public. I would ask that you mute your
personal devices. Uh Director Nimichek,
do you want questions as we go or hold
them till the end?
Okay, questions as we go. if you have
them, I'll try to um
acknowledge you with that. Director
Nimichek, can you kick it off and
introduce everybody? And here we go.
Thank you.
>> Absolutely. Vicki Neichek, public works.
I would like to kick off the meeting
starting with a why should we renovate
the municipal building? I'll be short
and sweet, I promise you. But this
building was built almost 50 years ago
and it has had no major renovations. As
I mentioned in a previous uh council
meeting, we've basically just put
lipstick on the pig. Um mechanical as we
I've just I'll just give a few examples
of some of the things that we're we have
challenges with. Um the open floor
design with the original uh building has
created some a lot of situations where
we have problems. The one of them being
the HVAC or the heating ventilation and
air conditioning system. The walls that
you put up have created a situation
where if it it could be 80° in this room
and 59 degrees in the room next door.
It's uh the the temperature basically is
just uncontrollable throughout the
building at this point. Um elevators, if
I don't know if you've all noticed, but
we have one elevator that's been
inoperable for nearly a month. Um they
don't make the parts we need anymore.
So, they're making those parts for us.
Um that's the kind of thing that we have
to deal with is the age of the
mechanical systems that are in this
building. um parts are just not we're
just not able to get them anymore. Um
the electrical system we I think
everybody probably remembers I think it
was last year we had a power outage. Um
we were unable to bring the building
back online. We had to delay opening the
building because we didn't have the
switch gears or the capacity to bring
our to just turn everything back on. It
just we just didn't have it. Um,
another thing with the electrical, we
just as a a note, we designed new
restrooms. We didn't um go through with
the building of those restrooms, but
just as a to show our electrical
capacity, we designed that build the
restrooms with hand dryers only. We
don't have the capacity to run hand
dryers in this building. The electrical
capacity. Um,
another piece is there was no, if you
remember back, if you're as old as I am,
there was no inter internet when this
building was built. I know a lot of
people that are probably listening to
this can't imagine not having internet,
but um, the new technology at that time
was correctable typewriters. I know
because I just had started in the
workforce. So now we have desktops,
laptops, twoin ones, iPads, phone, um
multiple screens. Everybody has screens
in their offices, screens on the walls,
double screens on the uh connected to
their computers. Everything is powered
and everything is connected. I mean, we
even have people who want to plug in an
ebike, you know, to so that they can
drive it to work and drive it home. Um,
lots of electrical drawing uh on this
building that we just never planned for
50 years ago.
Plumbing. Uh, the pipes are in pretty
good shape. The problem are the things
that connect the pipes. Those
deteriorate. Rubber just isn't what it
was 50 years ago. So, we are starting,
we're really starting to see failures in
the couplers, and those couplers are in
very difficult to reach areas. So, just
another reason that we need to look at
updating this building. Um, the fire
alarm system. When I first started
working here, you couldn't hear the fire
alarm if you were in your office or you
could only hear it if you were in the
hallway. With the open floor design, it
was designed so that you could hear it
so everybody could hear it if there were
no walls. But that just uh we had to
update that. But and we did. So you can
hear it now throughout the building. But
again, it's not interconnected. It's
interconnected with other systems, our
electrical system, our mechanical
system. So it needs to be designed so
that it works with those other systems.
We have basically cobbled together over
the years all of these systems and they
need to be rebuilt and work together
with current technology.
um our ADA st the ADA standards in this
building you can't get to the dis
you can't get even our um the ramps that
come down to the to the chairs they're
too steep for the AD current ADA
requirements. Um the elevators, you
can't put a stretcher in our elevators.
Won't fit. They have to carry the people
down the stairs.
Um,
we have three sets of bathrooms that are
not ADA accessible. The employees and
the public, since we added the two
restrooms back in the back here, just
outside the council chambers, we have to
direct employees and the public to those
restrooms if they need ADA accessible
restrooms.
Um, ADA overall,
the elected officials, the employees,
and especially the public, they just
deserve better. We need to renovate this
building. Um
space. We have an unusually
an unusually uh designed exterior. So it
leads to little cubby holes of space um
throughout the building. There's space
behind that seal that has been sitting
there
full of probably full of stoaged items
that have been there for quite some
time. But it's just a just to show that
there are so many inefficient spaces
that if we gutted the building and redid
everything, we would find so much more
space in this building to use. Um light,
one of our biggest things, people want
natural light. We don't have a lot of
it. Um we are going to add windows. If
we can do this renovation, windows will
be a major piece of the puzzle.
um security. I think we'll all agree
that we're all in a different place than
we were 50 years ago. We um we've gone
from being feeling safe in our
workplaces to not feeling safe in our
workplaces if we have the public
accessing every spot that we work. Um
we've gone from keys to fobs to badges.
We've added doors, taken doors out,
added walls, taken We've done all kinds
of things to our entry system. Again,
another cobbled together system. We add
fobs on doors. We add fobs on buildings.
We add fobs on on all kinds of things.
But again, those things need to be
designed in and work together with the
existing systems. Um, we have some
exterior cracking that needs to be
investigated and addressed.
So overall, these things can only be
addressed with a major renovation. So
that uh those are just some ideas.
There's a lot more of why this building
needs to be renovated, but I wanted to
give you just an an overview of how we
see it and what we're hoping to
accomplish is to get all of those things
fixed. So, with that said, um today
we're excited to share our um initial
vision for the future, and I will let
our design and project team,
uh introduce themselves.
So, hi, I'm Britt Morgan.
>> Oh,
hi, I'm Britt Morgan. I am vice
president of Plan One Architects and
Oh,
and I
it could be. Oh, there we go. Um, I am
vice president of plan architects and I
lead our Cheyenne office and I will be
the project architect for this project
and we're excited to be working with
this with you guys.
>> Good afternoon everyone. My name is
Jared Hoffman. I'm a principal architect
with plan one and I'll be working with
uh Brit and supporting the project.
>> Good afternoon, council members. Oh,
that's that works well. Mine works
better than yours, I think. I'm Christa
Plaza, president of Asenza Architecture,
and we will be the design lead on the
project together. We all really design
together, so we'll be working together
with Plan One. We really enjoy working
with them.
>> Hi, my name is uh Jeff Rogers and I am
an architect with Asenza. uh I'll be
working as a project manager on this
project.
>> So, we just wanted to share with you
kind of our project process that we've
done so far. Um you guys had a nice
spatial analysis done about a year ago.
So, what we wanted to do when we came in
is validate that spatial analysis. So,
we've done a couple surveys with
employees. We've met with all the
department heads. we've met several
times to kind of go through and make
sure departments are on the right level.
Making sure we have great public access
to the departments that need the most
and basically design where places are
going and who's near who and why
and uh part of that process is we will
be doing a estimates along every phase
of the project. So our conceptual
estimate will be done end of February.
Um, we have reviewed the estimate that
was done with the spatial analysis and
that was a great starting point and
it didn't include soft cost. So, that's
one thing that we'll definitely want to
make sure we're including when we
provide our conceptual estimate.
We will move into the schedule. I'm
going to let Jeff talk a little bit
about the schedule and u just a little
bit about process. We've been going
through this conceptual work together
and getting a lot of feedback from
everyone. So, we're here today to get
feedback from your team and learn more
about what you guys are looking for in
your council chambers as well.
>> Uh, Mr. President, um,
>> Councilman Wolf
>> through you. Um, first of all, I want to
thank all of you for being here and
really appreciate this is a incredibly
important, incredibly exciting project
and uh, Director Nimichek, thank you for
that review. It's really helpful as we
go out and talk to the public about just
the deficiencies of this building that
um why this is so critical for us. Um I
would like to at some point just to ask
you if you could tell us about your
prior experiences and your current
experiences with uh government buildings
sort of what you're seeing in the way of
you know design standards, design
criteria.
um what what you're hearing. I mean,
it's fascinating to look at a building
of this age and see how workspace has
changed so dramatically. Um but whenever
it's appropriate for you, Mr. Chairman,
with your with your permission obviously
to to have them just tell us about, you
know, what what kinds of things on an
overall kind of high concept level we uh
on the council and the mayor's office
and the department heads ought to be uh
thinking about. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
So, we wanted to uh take a look at a
schedule here that we've put together.
And what we've done is uh basically
broken out two schedules uh since the
council building or the senior center uh
was thrown into the mix after we kind of
set up the original schedule uh for the
uh municipal building itself. Um
ultimately one of our goals is to uh
complete the council building uh as
we're um basically uh um have that
completed so that the chambers can move
over and council office can move into
that building and we can begin
construction uh on this building. Um so
that's what has kind of dictated uh how
the schedule goes. Um so where we uh
where we've ended up is getting
completed with our schematic design uh
by the uh uh the 24th of uh uh or
somewhere around the uh the end of March
and that would be for both buildings. Um
at that point our uh schedule kind of
diverges and we quickly uh complete the
uh the drawings and start the uh the
permitting and uh um bidding process for
the council building uh such that it can
be complete that it can start
construction um at the uh end of summer.
Uh that's obviously uh um requires all
the necessary approvals and things like
that. Um and that would be completed
there at the uh uh when was that? That
was uh March of uh 2027. And that's
about when we would begin construction
uh there in mid-March of the uh the
municipal building. So that's where
we've
kind of sat with uh the the schedule.
>> Mr. President,
>> Dr. any
>> so through you Mr. President Jeff, in
looking at the construction you have up
there, I it makes sense to go with the
council building first. Um
the way you read that, but why are we
hiring the Seymar for the municipal
building a month before
the council building?
It should be the
it should be about the same timing um
that the semar rep will get. Uh this
usually we want to have the the semar
rep going off of the schematic uh cost
estimate. And so that's that's usually
the best time to uh get them involved.
Um
and that was roughly the same on both
projects. Uh it just ended up that our
our schematic design,
we just timed it out such that the
schematic design for both buildings
would be completed. We could get our
conceptual uh cost estimating done for
both both projects at the same time. At
that point, they would diverge uh in
terms of how quickly, you know, it's the
council building is obviously much
smaller, so it'll go much quicker. Uh
>> Mr. President, I guess my logic was if
we were starting construction on the on
the council building 6 to9 months 6 to 7
months prior to starting construction on
this building, we would hire that the
Seymar for
that project first and then my other I
guess then along those lines are you is
are you anticipating that the Seymar
will do both projects or will we have
two individuals?
That is um we were imagining that that
was our initial you know approach. Um
it'd be more much more simple to uh to
keep that uh in the hands of one uh
>> say one individual but you know one
person is you know uh kind of in charge
of both buildings because they will be
tied together. Uh I know that we'll be
um
we'll have to have internet and you know
the uh the communications between the
buildings will have to be connected. Um
so there's a lot of of internet
connection between the two buildings. So
that seemed to be the
>> Thank you, Mr. W. We've looked at it.
>> Thank you.
>> Uh if I may, I believe there is just a
typo. It should be the exact time frame.
So it should be the February 25th when
we go out for CM for both.
I agree. So sorry about that. But um a
little bit um I wanted to address
council member Wolf if I could and just
share a little bit about our background
before we jump into some of these
schematic plans. But we did we have been
doing a lot of research on different
municipalities and what what challenges
they're seeing. And I think probably one
of the biggest challenges we see. We we
do about 80% of our work is with
municipalities.
And so we're constantly seeing different
cities, different sizes, different
towns, jurisdictions, districts, all
sorts of different things. And um we
oftentimes I think the biggest one of
the biggest challenges is the
departments are always they're never
near each other as close to where they
want to be. So those adjacencies in the
space planning seem to not quite be
where they you know engineering wants to
be near building the building department
or you know we want to make sure there's
public facing and sometimes they have
public facing on all floors similar to
what your team has here in this
building. And so how do we you know kind
of fix that and and get those
adjacencies right? Get those team
members next to each other that want to
be next to each other for better and
improved communications. So, I think
that's one of the things we see a lot
more often than you'd realize. And so,
that's where we did a lot of, especially
last Friday, we did a lot of research
with the department heads or listen to
all the things they had to say about
what was important to them in terms of
communication with other department
heads and department team members. So, I
think that's one big thing to share.
But, but yeah, it's always interesting
seeing all the different jurisdictions
and cities and different departments.
So,
so yes. So, moving on. So, what we want
to do is go into the site diagram. So,
we're going to go ahead and share site
diagrams with you today. We're going to
share the building diagram of the
municipal building here and then finish
with the council chambers and then
finally go into a little interior design
exercise for fun at the end. So, let's
look at the site really quickly to get
everyone oriented. Remind me if I'm not
right in my microphone. Uh, let's see.
So, we are currently in the municipal
building right here. And this is our
parking lot to the north, just to get
everyone oriented.
And then this is the records building to
the north here or what will be the
records building. And then the new city
council building to the east, northeast.
Does that make sense to everyone?
>> Excellent. Okay. So, yeah. And what some
of the things we're working on is we're
going to be starting with our landscape
team once we get some of the bu
buildings a little bit more settled in
all these department meetings and
looking really at the connection between
these three buildings and the parking
lots. Where are people parking? How are
they using the space? Where they're
connecting to each building? And
sometimes you might have people going
from building to building. So what's the
best route? And really our landscape
architect and our design team will work
to really closely together to to have
some really nice connections and
walkways to each building.
So that's that site plan. Any questions
about the site plan at first glance? I
think it's basically what it is now and
we'll start to get into the new site
plans in the next month or so. So this
is the municipal building.
I'm going to zoom in a little bit to the
first floor plan. And so one of the big
things we've discussed with the team is
including a nicer new entry with an
elevator that actually can accommodate
um accessible um basically a stretcher
for accessibility. So we want to make
sure that's in that space. We'd like to
have a really nice entry from you know
basically this parking lots to the north
to orient you on this sheet too. We
tried to keep north up on all of the
sheets just for your reference. uh but
having a nice new front vestibule where
you come in and what we also want to do
there's been a lot of discussion about
security and a lot of people have you
know concerns about security and making
sure you're all safe everyone's safe in
this building that's working here. So um
we really wanted people to come in and
have a secure zone but this also you
also want it to be inviting to the
public. So how do you do that and
connect with the public but then become
secure beyond a certain point. So you
can see this is kind of the public zone
if you can see my hand here on the
screen. Let me zoom in just a hair more.
Um and so this is the HR. We have HR
because they're public facing out in the
front, the city clerk and building and
permitting. So those seem to be the most
commonly um accessed points for the
public to meet with the engineers and
the HR team and the city clerk's team.
Um, we did we we do have a lot of
comments from our meeting last Friday.
I'll just say that that we haven't
incorporated all those comments in yet.
Um, but we got a lot of great feedback
on some of some of these plans so far.
So then, um, we would also have public
restrooms.
And then beyond that point, you can see
there's kind of a secure zone and
there's discussion about the exact
location of where this all becomes
secure. But then then you would enter
into the compliance construction
engineering um and meeting spaces for
those teams. Um another big item that
came up was having meeting rooms
downstairs. There's a lot of people
going up and down on the floors in this
building. Um this happens in a lot of
other municipal buildings we've seen and
and a lot of uh team members don't want
the public going to all the different
levels. So we're trying to get meeting
room spaces down to the first level. So
you can call up to the team member that
needs to come down and meet with the
public. So we're trying to get that
connection to the downstairs so they
don't have to go up and down through
through the building and travel through
the building. So basically we have that
as a secure point.
Does that make sense so far? All right,
let's see. And then let's move to the
second floor. So, if you're coming in,
you would take this elevator um once
well, most people won't take the
elevator because the public access will
be downstairs, but if you work in the
building, you can take this elevator up
to the second level or if you're meeting
someone, you need to go upstairs, you
can go to that level, you would most
likely need to be buzzed in for safety.
Um, so there's that and you would do
that by going to the front desk. So,
that's where that secure point happens.
And then upstairs on that second level
right now we have the public works
planning department um engineering and
the no department and DDA. So all of
those team members also have meeting
rooms. Some of them will also have
meeting rooms within their office spaces
too but those might become a little bit
more public facing if people do have to
come to that second level and be
escorted up to that level or have a
badge to go up to that level.
>> Mr. Chair Mr.
President
>> Dr.
>> um are the and maybe you're going to
talk about this later but are these all
open areas or are there offices within
the different departments?
>> Good question. Those are all offices
within the different departments. So
there will be and that's what we met
Friday to discuss was we talked about
who needs closed offices. Can there be
some open offices for you know more open
office communications? You know some
people need more privacy. So, who needs
closed offices? Who needs open offices?
We actually had a number of diagrams we
shared um with and I can even show you
that we talked about. Oh, it's not that
one. It's this one. We talked about
different office spaces, different
layouts, different furniture. Um, you
know, we're not to the stage where we
pick out every piece of furniture yet,
but we will be doing the FFN package and
going through that in a lot of detail
with all the team members. But what we
wanted to do is start laying out the
spaces. But first we wanted to get to
the adjacencies with all the departments
and who is on each floor. Yeah, good
question.
So then let's see that's the second
floor. Let's go to the third floor. And
on the third floor we have the um city
attorneys, the community wreck and
events. Then we have the mayor's office,
treasurer, and we we placed the mayor's
office in the center of the treasurer
and city attorney. We thought that would
be a good connection. Um and then um
meeting and training rooms and then IT
space. There was discussions at the last
meeting that it might be better on the
second floor. So we might be, you know,
fine-tuning this, especially since we
had a lot of great feedback on Friday
last week. So um those are some good
things to think about. But yeah, we'll
be rearranging that. And of course on
each floor, we did try to put meeting
rooms because that seems to be a big um
big challenge in this building is not
having enough meeting room space. So
that was something that was we've heard
and wanted to address.
So let's see other than that if you see
this MEP is mechanical electrical
plumbing that's currently where all your
mechanical systems are housed and some
of that may be changing based on the new
mechanical systems once we start working
together with our engineers closely. So
that will be um good to see because that
might free up some space and it yeah
just depends on how the how the
mechanical engineers want to lay things
out for us.
So, did I miss anything? Brent, can you
think of anything else?
Okay. Any questions about the municipal
building?
>> Go ahead.
>> Um, Councilman Labour.
>> Thank you, M. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
One of my principal concerns is windows
and lighting. I mean, uh, I don't see
this. The schematic doesn't really
demonstrate that, but,
um,
how many windows you going to have? I
mean,
>> so, let's talk about that. So, on this
drawing, you're seeing actually these
are windows. We don't have the exact,
we're actually working through the
design of those windows as we speak and
um, and probably going to meet after
this meeting to go over some window
layouts. We're going to start working on
the exterior. Um, but these are
proposing a lot of new windows. We'll
probably have different arrangements.
They may not be exactly like we drew it
here because this is very conceptual and
schematic. But yeah, the goal is to get
as many windows as we can and have
natural daylight because that is that's
one of the things that was shared with
us many times and and um yeah, we've
just heard it over and over again. So,
and the idea is we do a lot of office
spaces where we bring in natural
daylight through. We might have offices
on the perimeter, but then you bring
natural daylight. you open up and maybe
don't have offices along every wall so
that you open things up to the center of
the space and you get light to the
center. So, we're looking for a lot of
ways to do that to really incorporate
daylighting and make it feel a lot more
open than how it feels now.
>> Thank you.
>> Good question. Councilman Esco.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Through you, uh,
the briefly touched on about it being
moved to the from the third back to the
second floor and from that end of the
building to this end. But since the
whole building's going to be reupdated
electrically, it doesn't really matter
where we put it based on the amount of
need that they have for uh their
computer needs and everything.
>> Yeah. And I think they they actually we
had a a good meeting with it on Tuesday
actually and and went through what how
it would be beneficial for them or where
it was best um best to locate them and
they they noted the second floor just
because they could pull wires from the
second to the third and to the first
floor. So basically they're in the
center of the building. So that was what
they were really thinking would be the
best for them. So we'll start to lay
that out and work with them more on it.
But yeah, and there were discussions
about we want to make sure the new IT
room is built before we take down the we
want to keep the IT in full operations
of course because it services a few
places and um and then once that new
space is built they can pull the wires
get it all set and ready to transition
in a day or so kind of thing. So well
might take more than a day but but yeah
we just want to keep things up and
operational.
>> Thank you for that. That that answers my
follow-up question.
>> Thank you. Oh, good.
>> Councilman Wolf,
>> uh, Mr. President, thank you. Uh,
through you, um, do you anticipate any,
um, significant structural issues? I
know you mentioned that there's some or
actually, uh, Director Neichek mentioned
there's there's there's cracking on the
exterior of the building. Um, but, um,
are there any other foundational issues
or any other those costs can obviously
be really significant. Um, and are there
any structural issues associated with
adding windows?
>> Definitely adding windows. So, with
windows, we have brick on the most of
the outside of the building, but there
we actually do a lot of large openings
in old buildings from many different
years and many different ages. And yeah,
really just you have to structurally
reinforce it. You have to have lentils
over the windows. It's basically adding
a certain amount of steel to support the
roof loads and everything above. So,
there's there are ways of doing that. We
actually really enjoy maybe Another
answer to your first question is we
enjoy build bringing old buildings back
to life. It's something we we specialize
in and we do a lot of renovations,
probably more renovations than new
construction lately just because we do
enjoy the challenge of bringing you know
1960s and 70s buildings back to life.
But I'll let Brit answer a little bit
about the geotech and the survey and the
yeah structural.
So we recently had our geotech
engineering
to around the area that there's settling
issues. Um they have found that there's
a lot of fines but what our structural
engineer is thinking is maybe the
settling happened in the 80s when there
was a big flood in the area. So what
we're doing right now is where we have
points to see if it's still settling or
not or if that settling has been
resolved and it was an old issue. So we
are definitely looking into that and
making sure you know we'll fix any issue
that there may be
and I do believe there's currently in
the budget there was cost to fix that
like an allowance but by the you know
once we get to the details of that we
will make sure we have the right cost in
the budget to do that.
>> Thank you. Anyone else on the dis? Any
other
Jennifer? Do we have anybody online?
>> Yep. Mr. Moody, you can go ahead.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> All right. Uh, thank you. Uh, Mr. uh,
chairman, I just want to double check.
Can everybody hear me?
>> Yes, we can.
>> All right. Thank you guys. Appreciate
it. Good afternoon. Good afternoon.
Thank you for being here, everybody. I
just had one question for my uh,
followup question. Have you guys done
any public forums with regards to this
like at the library or, you know,
inviting the public to see what
potentially the changes could be to the
uh building?
>> Any public meetings?
>> We haven't done any public meetings yet,
but we would love to do public meetings.
I think that's a great idea if that's
something you're all open to.
>> Oh, absolutely.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> And then a follow, Mr. Chairman.
>> Yes. Go ahead, Councilman Woody.
>> Yeah. Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman,
through you. Um, then my second question
is I notice for the second and third
floor on that plan there is what you're
saying is is that constituents and the
public, they don't have any access to
them up there at all. It'd be blocked
off. Is that what the plan is saying
that the second and third floor would be
blocked off?
>> They would be open, but not completely
open like the first floor and you'd have
to have a badge and you'd have to have
someone come get you. kind of like what
we have or you'd have to be buzzed in
and permitted to go in so that it was
secure and you just didn't have people
wandering to the second and third floor.
But that can be I mean we def I think
that's definitely something we have to
discuss when we get our security team on
board and what the sequence is and how
how secure you want it and you also
don't want to be closed to the public,
right? Because it's a public facing
building, but you also want to be safe
as well.
>> All right, one more followup, Mr.
Chairman.
>> Yes, Councilman Woody. Go ahead. Yeah.
Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you. Um, yeah, thank you for that. Yeah,
just I've had some constituents
concerned about that if it's too secure.
Um, from that perspective that it's
going to feel like they're not welcome
to go through the building. Um, right
now you can do it. And, you know, from
my perspective, that's a good thing
because right now there are uh, like for
instance, the plane department really
great. They have it open. You can go
there, ask for help. parks and
recreation they even on their door
please come in and talk to us. I just
look that look at it from that
perspective and definitely private
offices you're not allowed to go in as
the public that's been decided by courts
and all that but just having that open
window there like planning or has now I
think that's the best one out there
because then the public feels like they
can go there to all his various
departments and get the necessary help.
So, I'm just saying what constituents
have said because I know in Paleoto,
California a couple years ago did
something like that and they got
backlash even from people that supported
their city council there. And there is a
letter to the editor there that's from
2023 if anybody's interested. So, I was
just reading that um before I uh got on
this meeting, but that's all I have.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you, Councilman. Any other online,
Jennifer?
Okay, I think we're good to go.
>> Wonderful. Thank you. And that's a great
comment, too, because it is it's a
public building, but you also want to be
safe. So, what is the the right design
for that? And I think that's going to be
a discussion for quite a few months as
we move forward with more design
details. So, I will hand this off to
Brit to go over the council chambers.
I'm going to zoom in. Let me know if I
zoom too fast or too slow.
So, we've met a couple times with our
core group on the council building and
we definitely want to get your feedback
as well. Um, right now we're looking at
actually making the new entry on the
southwest corner instead of the
northwest where it currently is. Um,
that way you have better access to the
parking garage since I know a lot of
meetings are night. A lot of people are
parking in that parking garage. So, that
there's easy access from there. And then
there's also an access from the
municipal building itself. And what we
are looking at is trying to stay with
the structure of the building. We've got
the council chambers turned so that
we're utilizing existing structure and
the existing height of the building. And
currently the fixed seating would be
about 80. So it's a little bit bigger
than what we've got here. And the
committee room would have an operable
partition
that would be able to expand similar to
what you have now except it would be
behind. So you'd have expandable space
that you can actually still see the
council.
And in the back we've got the council
offices where there'd be workspace where
you know if we need to make copies
during a meeting it'd be right behind
there. There's a staff office and then
also an executive session meeting room.
So, council chambers currently or
council office, sorry, would be similar
to what you guys have now or be an open
space where you'd all have a desk area
to work at. And then there's enough
space in this building that we could
have another tenant. We have not
assigned a certain tenant yet, but
there's space for five offices and
meeting rooms as well as break rooms.
And the yellow are the restrooms which
are existing. So they had recently
renovated those. So we're thinking use a
similar
area so that we're not redoing work
that's already been completed.
>> Questions. Uh Dr. Emmens.
>> Um thank you. Is the are the restrooms
ADA accessible now?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> And then we did add two single user
restrooms as well. Single user. Yeah. In
the pink by the staff bathroom. Council
Escoel.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Do you for the
public to enter council chambers? Is
there just the one entry and exit?
>> There are two uh there's one through the
committee room and then one through the
council chambers.
>> And follow up, Mr. Chair. I mean for the
public. So we have two here for the
public.
>> Yes.
>> This one there's only one for the public
because it looks like the back is for
us.
So there's actually in the green there's
a little stair out the back of the dis
right there. That would be the council
entrance.
>> The only one for the public if you look
>> two for the
>> she's
>> I didable.
>> Yeah.
>> And then down here. Okay.
>> So on that Mr. chair through that when
they come through the meeting room into
the chamber.
>> Yes.
>> And there is an operable partition if
you can see my hand here where that
would mainly be opened up until you
broke out for a committee meeting room a
committee meeting essentially. Does that
help?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, usually that will be open.
Yeah. I see we're Yeah.
>> Mr. President,
>> Dr. Really,
>> I also wanted to point out that in
council chambers, it will not be sloped.
It will be a flat
um room. Otherwise, that would be very I
mean, it's a flat floor now and it would
be very expensive to put a slope in if
we really desired that. So, I don't
remember what did you say the das would
be raised
>> like two feet above the
>> above the chamber.
Councilman.
Yeah. Okay.
Councilman Wolf.
>> Mr. President, thank you through you.
Um, what are you seeing in your work
with other uh municipalities um in terms
of this kind of a hearing room? I mean,
are you seeing that they have these
fixed theater kind of seats or are
people going to a much more flexible
arrangement?
I would say it's probably 50/50 because
some people want it just depends on the
on the council members and the city or
jurisdiction and some of them want this
kind of more formal fixed seating and
some like to have open seats so that you
can rearrange the room. You can do
different things. You perhaps you know
you do a really large workshop or some
kind of public hearing. That way you can
open up the seats and put boards up and
have people walk around if it's some
kind of public workshop or something
else different. And so it depends on if
you want it to be a little more flexible
versus a little more formal. So I think
that's a a good decision for your team
to make and think about. I don't know R
if you have things to add.
>> We have included a aisle down the center
so you're not having to, you know,
scooch all the way in
>> so that it's easier access for both
sides.
>> That does help.
>> Okay. Um we have a question online.
Jennifer,
>> Mr. Mr. Moody, you can go ahead.
>> All right. Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Through you, um, looking at the our city
council offices. So, where would the
public go to access us um to serve our
constituents? Cuz I was looking there on
that diagram and I don't see can they go
through that one door to access us
because I do have constituents meet with
me from time to time in the city council
office.
>> Yes. So you would go through this door
and come into the council offices this
way. Do you see my arrow online?
>> Yes, ma'am.
>> Okay. So yeah, right now that that is
how you would access the council
offices.
So and I would I would say just to stay
secure, you know, you could have this as
a secure access and buzz people in. Are
you thinking it needs to be open access?
>> Um Mr. Chairmanu.
>> Yes. Uh thank you, Mr. Chairmanu. Um, I
personally think it should be open
because we're here to serve the people
and we want to be as accessful as we can
for the people. That's that's my
perspective. I mean, maybe some people
differ, but that's just how I feel in
terms of accessibility from my
perspective.
>> Thank you. Any further questions?
Anyone? U Councilman Labor.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Um, we took a tour of this adjacent
property here that we're going to have
this design
hopefully happen. And we're a long way
from owning it. And that that really
concerns me because
as I understood it, the chaos in
Washington DC has really impacted the
HUD office that has approval and final
word on this. So, um I mean, if you're
talking August, uh construction,
um I'm just very curious. I mean, I know
we can't at this point really say for
sure,
but obviously, uh utilizing this space
and having this type of a council area
would be very beneficial,
but how do we know we're going to be
able to do that?
>> That's
I don't know who to ask that. Um
maybe uh Amber, can you give us an
update real quick?
The status if you will, please
get an answer.
Chairman through you. Um, Amber Ash,
chief of staff for the city of Cheyenne.
In regards to acquisition of that
building, um, we have sent over the
formal offer or the letter of intent. I
guess it's not the finalized offer. Um,
it will have to go through a HUD
process. Um, the HUD process will take
some time. Um, there
we don't control HUD schedule as was
noted. Um and certainly that will depend
on a lot of different factors. Um
however, we have been working um in
tandem with uh CHA on that building and
um trying to work through the logistics
to move it along in anticipation of a
timeline very similar to this um with
the concept that we would complete that
building first before construction of
this building would go. Um I think it's
very important if we can make that work
um to do that simply because
it ensures that public continues to have
continuity um for public meetings and
city council meetings um and that access
and so um we have been working very
closely with CHA and have let HUD know
as well.
>> Follow up.
>> Thank you. Okay. Thank you. Any further
question? Uh Dr. Renie.
>> Um, Mr. President, I just want to
comment on the tan area up on the
northwest side that um it's projected or
anticipated that we'll either put
another city department in there or
perhaps
um lease it to
a 501c3 or kind of a non-governmental
organization. If we I want to remind my
colleagues that if we do not do
something like that, Jennifer would be
the only one in that building.
And I think she'd probably like to have
some other bodies in there.
>> Is that right, Jennifer?
>> Uh, yeah, some other bodies would be
really nice. I mean, I I have still some
concerns with this. I mean, and we don't
have to get it a long way where my
office is to the front door, you know. I
mean, I think those questions are your
expectation of what your expectation is
about that building being open and
available for the public. I mean, I
think those are some things internally
we need to talk about.
>> Thank you, Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Um, I have a
question about the um in the council cha
chambers now that we've had new
legislation that allows
uh concealed carry of firearms in public
buildings like this. Are we going to
have a dis that has some kind of
security built into it or does any of
this has that been reflected?
>> Yes, we have been requested to provide
um so that is the plan and then also
that's why we have the kind of the
hidden door behind
is that so you have a way to get off the
dis.
Further questions?
Uh, Jennifer,
>> can we Mr. Moody took his hand down? Uh,
Mr. Moody, did you have another
question?
>> No, ma'am.
>> Mr. President, did I have another
question if we can go back? Jeff, can we
go back to the schedule?
So, as Jennifer just stated, she still
has some concerns that we maybe need to
resolve amongst ourselves.
Looking at the schedule, if we're going
to do that, when do you want the
information if we want changes made
beyond what's conceptual here?
>> Are you talking about for the council
chambers? Yeah.
>> Well, yeah, just the the council
building.
>> I would say as soon as possible, but I
obviously a hard date. be good to give
you guys some time to look at it. So, I
would say it would be great to have
something
within two or three weeks. How does that
sound?
>> Okay. I just we need I mean
>> so I can give you
>> if we're going to if we're going to do
that, we need to know what your deadline
is. So, what your drop dead date is and
>> Okay.
>> So, just to get that out.
>> Okay. And it'd be great to you know, we
really want to get this into the
computer, too. So, we have a few more
office spaces laid out. This is very
conceptual at this point. So there will
be a couple phases. I feel like it, you
know, we really want you you all to be
able to share as much input as possible.
So um we might get initial feedback and
then put maybe say two weeks initial
feedback and then after that we can get
more things into the computer and then
we have another chance to make more
comments because that really yeah we we
don't want just to have one plan. We'd
like to have multiple kind of design.
>> Thank you Mr. President. Dr.
U Mr. President, one more question. When
you showed this to the different
departments or in the in the building,
what was the general consensus of the
staff?
>> Are you talking for the municipal
building or for this in general?
>> Um, I think they were all pretty excited
about the windows
and having the opportunity to lay out
their departments how they want it. Um,
you know, offices have been added here
and there and really it's very
inefficient. Um, you know, I we walked
the building a couple of times and it's
just really weird organization of
departments and we can make it a lot
more efficient, a lot more open and
useful and efficient for the employees.
So,
>> Councilman Wolf,
>> uh, thank you, Mr. President. uh through
you um on the on the first page the just
the site plan layout c can I ask you to
label the residential tower as like the
senior residential tower I don't want
the public to think that we're actually
living there as well as working there um
and even though I might uh in fact there
might be some members of the public who
think I probably should go in so uh but
and you also might label the dental
office too which is um in which is
blocked out there but doesn't doesn't
have any labeling so that people can
understand what that is as well. Thank
you, Mr. President.
>> Thank you. Further questions?
>> Uh Jennifer,
>> Mr. Moody, you can go ahead.
>> All right. Uh thank you, Mr. Chairman,
through you. Um
uh just have a question related to the
windows. Um we do live in Hail Alley
here in the United States.
What type of windows are we looking to
install? Because otherwise there'd be a
lot of claims.
>> Please.
>> Very good question. Um, we actually
specify high performance glass that has
a lot more than just hail hail damage
qualities. Although, you know, if you
get 5 in hail, which we have some
jurisdictions we work with that that is
tough to challenge, but two to three
inch, we seem to be doing very well with
these high performance windows. So we
have a lot of high performance glass,
vitro glass at certain brands that we
like to use that are both good for hail
but also good for solar gain, solar heat
gain coefficients. They have
reflectivity to them. So it really keeps
the sun, it lets the right kind of sun
and daylight in and keeps the heat and
and uh and solar gain out, I guess you
could say. So good question.
>> Anything further, Mr. Moody?
>> No, sir.
>> Okay.
Anybody else? Oh, I'm sorry. Councilman
Labour.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. I see this on
this first sheet. The vacated portion of
West 21st Street there next to our
parking facility. Um,
that design is the primary entrance and
exit of that. Well, there's two, but um
where where did this vacation idea come
from?
That was uh probably my mistake. I
thought I heard that in the last meeting
that that was uh that portion was
vacated and maybe I misinterpreted that.
Um
but that isn't you know it was it's not
proposed. It's it would stay exactly the
same. There was some talk about you know
the uh the council building does have a
lot of visibility down 21st Street. um
where it's kind of hidden from all the
other streets, you know, being set back
in there from Tomes and and uh from
O'Neal. Um and there may be an
opportunity uh there.
So that was
>> Thank you.
Is there anything else you'd like to uh
present today?
We have one other thing that's going to
be an interior visioning exercise. And
so we we would like to encourage you to
put these red, yellow, and green dots on
this vision board we're going to hand
out. We have that.
And then um while Jeff is handing those
out, I will explain. So the red dots,
you're you're going to get this
collection of images. I'll share these
up on the screen, too, but you'll get
red dots. Those are for things you don't
like. And these are for character of the
design. Um, green dots for things you
really like. Um, yellow dots for maybe
you like something in the image. Maybe
you like a color. Maybe you like a
finish. Maybe you like just the general
feel of it, but you don't like something
else. And then um you get one special
blue dot for your favorite image. So
you'll see there are a number of um
chambers spaces. There's meeting room
spaces. Um, and then there are four
color palettes. We al also like to start
designing with an understanding of what
you guys want in your building because
this building is for you and your
community and it's not for us. It's we
really want to make it part of something
you want it to feel like for your
community.
So, go ahead and put the dots on and
then we're going to talk about it for a
few minutes on our time.
More
>> your favorite. Yep. And yellow is maybe
you're on the fence about something.
One dot per image.
>> Yeah.
>> One blue.
>> One blue. One for your very
If you if they're all your favorites,
then you can put blue dots on those.
Oh, here.
I'm done.
I'm not done yet.
Slow group.
Yes. So, choose your favorite color
scheme.
Can I take
Thank you.
I'll get it to you. I'll get it to them.
We'll share.
Uh
>> oh, we're close with our time.
See, we really need four hours to do do
this.
Mr. Chairman.
>> Um, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you, can I address another question to
this? Um, actually following up on Mr.
Moody's question about the windows, it
it um occurred to me that what what
kinds of um energy efficiency designs,
you know, he HVAC
designs are are you thinking that we
might be able to employ in this building
to reduce energy costs, uh make the
building, you know, more generally
comfortable, save money for for the
taxpayers. Um, assuming we can, you
know, pay for what might be the
additional cost of those features.
>> And I can address some of that. Maybe
Brit can as well, but we're our goal is
to always make the buildings as
sustainable as possible. Some teams want
lead certification, some do not. Late
most most lately, I'd say we go by a
lead checklist, but we don't certify the
building. That's what a lot of
jurisdictions are doing because they
don't want to spend the money on the
certification and the plaque, but they
want it to perform very highly. So, we
work with all of our engineers to do
that. And I think it's it's up to you
all how how much do you want to put into
that sustainability? But there's so many
things we can do that are smart and
efficient that don't take additional
money to. Some do take money, right?
Some do cost um certain dollar amount,
but some things are just smart design
and like picking out good windows that
perform highly and well and energy
efficient mechanical systems and things
like that are all part of what we would
design to just smart design I would say.
>> And to add on to that, uh we also have
lighting controls that would be
implemented in the building. So if a
space becomes unoccupied, the light
would turn off. um you know, dimmable
switches for light so people can control
how much light they want in their space.
Um and then also having the opportunity
to turn off your lights if you have an
exterior window
thing, too.
>> That's great.
>> Followup. Thank you very much, Mr.
Chairman. Um we replaced the boilers on
the roof not too long ago, three or four
years ago. I I think I wasn't here then,
but um and this may be too down in the
weeds, but I mean, are are are you to
the point where you believe you can
actually continue to use those? And do
we have any issues with the roof?
So, I've been talking with our engineer
and currently we're planning on keeping
the boiler and chiller that you guys
have replaced recently and um utilizing
that for the system, making sure it's
sized properly and everything for what
we're planning on doing.
>> The roof, we'll take a look at the roof
to see if it needs to be replaced when
we do the renovation as well.
>> Councilman label. Thank you, Mr.
Chairman. Um this is one of the most
important points as far as I'm concerned
and a very very uh
meaningful part of this design and I'm
not sure looking at this um how the
council deis is is going to be built but
speaking as a person who has spent a lot
of time uh addressing the council prior
to myction ction and during my uh brief
hiatus. It's intimidating.
This this is like a bench of a
courtroom.
This is not the nearer to that level of
uh that we see over at the county
courthouse. Um I'm not sure exactly the
measurement, but they are up on a little
riser, but they're not anything like
this. And I think that we all uh can ask
or discuss this with whomever uh no
matter what they're coming down here
for. Uh they generally uh are
it's intimidating. It is you you're not
off to the right start. And when people
have that spirit, I think they get
testy. So I I'm very much in favor of
making sure that what we do uh is a is a
deis that uh is appropriate and this one
certainly is not and if this opportunity
is here I you know obviously this
rendering is quite attractive but I just
wanted to make that point because I I'm
going to be emphasizing that as we go
along. Um it's it's so important and
particularly I think with I'm not sure
what security we're going to be having
to do. Uh this is incredibly difficult
with people and this situation we're
living in. But we really want to be
offering that opportunity to talk to us
in a setting that is not nearly like
this one. Thank you.
Further questions?
Anything else you'd like to present
today?
>> I I would just like to go around and
talk through your your dots that you put
on here and maybe each of you can share
something that's really important to you
about the council chambers.
I don't know if you want to start.
>> You want to start with Dr. Ren.
>> Dr. R.
question.
>> Mr. President, I've been attending their
meetings
all along, so I think I've gotten my
input in on that.
>> All right, Dr.
>> Um, thank you. I I agree with uh
Councilman Labborn that if we can have
something that's more welcoming for the
DAS but also safe, I'm much more um in
support of that.
Councilman Wolf
>> and pretty
>> uh thank you Mr. Chairman through you.
Um I'm I'm willing to defer to uh
Councilman Renie and and his judgments
on and other people in this. I agree on
the uh DAS. I think actually a more
flexible seating arrangement would add a
lot more utility to the council space.
um regarding colors and other things.
Uh uh just a plan to just stay out of
that debate and not complicate your
lives. So, thank you.
>> Thank you, Councilman Lemore. Anything
else?
>> Made my comment.
>> Councilman Esco,
>> Mr. truth. You You know what I liked
when we were at the school board
uh
their setup there the audiovisisual
aspects as well as giving the public the
opportunity.
I I guess they do on these screens, but
they're just too small for them. Uh I've
seen people out in in the public
squinting, some even using their cameras
to take a picture of it, then enlarging
it.
Uh haven't seen any binoculars or
telescopes out there yet, but
uh I think that the uh
uh audiovisisual part of it would be
good. Uh Jennifer uh who do we have left
online? Do we have Councilman Moody?
>> No,
>> everybody's gone.
>> Okay. All right. Anything else?
>> I believe that's everything. Thank you
for your input and we hope to have more
chances to have more input from you.
>> Oh, you will.
>> Believe me. Wonderful. You will.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. With that
>> Oh, do you have
>> I'm sorry.
>> Oh,
Mr. President, um would you like us to
sub kind of uh email you the hard dates
uh that you would that we would like um
to have comments uh back so then we can
um respond and then
>> I think hard dates uh if you can compile
what we've given you there and give us a
little idea what the as a group think
what we're where we're at that would be
great.
>> Thank you.
>> Is there anything else the council would
like in the interim here?
Okay. Yes, sir.
>> I just want to finish with thank you for
giving us your time today to present
this. Um,
>> I know that schedules were always going
to be a question. They're always tight.
They're always aggressive
>> and then when we take the roadblocks and
the bumps in the road, we adjust as we
go. So,
>> thank you.
>> Hopefully, we'll we'll stay on track and
get this built, but
we'll see what happens. But thanks again
for everybody. And if you have any
questions, please let us know.
>> Thank you. Uh, one final question. Do we
want to try to get together sometime in
the next two weeks?
Okay. We'll see. Uh, we'll see what we
can put together as far as a date uh for
the council to get together and
informally just discuss this. Of course,
we'll have to notice it, but um we'll
see what the schedule looks like. If
there are dates that you absolutely
cannot attend, why don't you let
Jennifer know that and we'll try to work
around those. With that, uh, we'll
adjourn. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.